Hi everyone, my name is Albert and I will be presenting the lecture on efficient transformer
안녕하세요 여러분, 제 이름은 Albert입니다. 효율적인 변압기에 대한 강의를 진행하겠습니다.
for CS86.
CS86용.
So what are we covering today?
오늘은 무엇을 다룰까요?
I'll give a quick review of the attention mechanism in transformers and then explain
트랜스포머의 어텐션 메커니즘을 간략하게 검토한 다음 설명하겠습니다.
the time and space complexity of a traditional transformer and why that would be a problem.
기존 변압기의 시간 및 공간 복잡성과 이것이 문제가 되는 이유.
I've finally presented several solutions proposed over the past, including sparse transformers,
나는 희소 변압기를 포함하여 과거에 제안된 몇 가지 솔루션을 마침내 제시했습니다.
lean former, linearized tension, long former, and resonant feature tension and so on.
린 포머, 선형화된 장력, 롱 포머, 공명 특징 장력 등이 있습니다.
These are of course not all of them, but due to time and constraint, these are all we will
물론 이것이 전부는 아니지만, 시간과 제약으로 인해 이것만 하겠습니다.
be covering today.
오늘은 취재해.
In the end, I will present the get-up project comparing the performance of all efficient
마지막으로 모든 효율적인 겟업의 성능을 비교하는 겟업 프로젝트를 제시하겠습니다.
transformers.
변압기.
So just a quick review of the attention mechanism.
그럼 주의 메커니즘을 간단히 살펴보겠습니다.
On the left, we define a bunch of values, begin as a sequence length, Lh is the number
왼쪽에는 일련의 값을 정의하고 시퀀스 길이로 시작하며 Lh는 숫자입니다.
of pairs, usually 8, there's some model in the embedding size, already 512, and this
쌍(보통 8개), 임베딩 크기가 이미 512인 일부 모델이 있습니다.
k, which is called to demodel divided by h, is 64.
디모델링을 위해 호출된 k를 h로 나눈 값은 64입니다.
So the input sequence is embedded into x, which is dimension n times demodel, and then
따라서 입력 시퀀스는 차원 n 배 디모델인 x에 포함됩니다.
the input is put through 8 separate heads, each containing weaknesses which x will multiply
입력은 8개의 개별 헤드를 통해 전달되며, 각 헤드에는 x가 곱할 약점이 포함되어 있습니다.
by, and the dimensions are of demodel times decay, and to obtain so that we can obtain
에 의해, 치수는 변형 시간 붕괴이며, 우리가 얻을 수 있도록 얻습니다.
the accurate key and value.
정확한 키와 값.
Then the attention is calculated by taking the softmax of q times k transposed divided
그런 다음 q x k의 소프트맥스를 전치된 값으로 나누어 어텐션을 계산합니다.
by square root of decay times, then closing time to iv, and finally the results from each
붕괴 시간의 제곱근, 종료 시간을 iv로, 마지막으로 각 결과
head are concedinated and multiplied by a final width matrix to obtain the output.
헤드에 최종 너비 행렬을 곱하여 출력을 얻습니다.
So let's then look at where the complexity comes from, recall the attention function,
그러면 복잡성이 어디서 오는지 살펴보고 주의 기능을 기억해 봅시다.
the attention q, k, and v is called to soften the x, blah, blah, blah, where the dimension
x, 어쩌고 저쩌고, 저쩌고를 부드럽게 하기 위해 주의 q, k, v가 호출됩니다. 여기서 차원은
of q is called dimension of k, which is called to n times decay, so the calculation of q
q의 차원을 k의 차원이라고 하며, 이는 n번 붕괴라고 부르므로 q의 계산은 다음과 같습니다.
times k transposed will thus cause an order of n squared times decay.
따라서 k를 곱하면 n제곱 곱하기 붕괴가 발생합니다.
As for the space complexity, storing the attention matrix, which is this part, would
공간복잡도에 관해서는 이 부분인 Attention Matrix를 저장하면
cause all n squared space complexity for each head, so the total of space complexity
각 헤드에 대해 모든 n 제곱 공간 복잡도가 발생하므로 전체 공간 복잡도는
would be all of n squared h, therefore if we have a very long sequence, much longer
모두 n 제곱 h가 될 것입니다. 따라서 매우 긴 수열이 있으면 훨씬 더 길어집니다.
when there are much longer than decay and sub-h, time and space cost would be quadratic
붕괴 및 하위 h보다 훨씬 긴 경우 시간 및 공간 비용은 2차가 됩니다.
to the sequence length, which would be very terrible if the sequence is very long, this
시퀀스 길이가 매우 길면 매우 끔찍할 것입니다.
would have a bad impact on the scalability of the transformer and really increase its
변압기의 확장성에 나쁜 영향을 미치고 실제로 그 확장성을 증가시킵니다.
resource consumption, this would also effect this adoption to all sorts of situations such
자원 소비, 이는 또한 다음과 같은 모든 종류의 상황에 대한 채택에 영향을 미칠 것입니다.
as image completion and audio recognition and so on.
이미지 완성 및 오디오 인식 등.
So to counter this situation, many has come over the solutions, here we list a bunch of
따라서 이러한 상황에 대응하기 위해 많은 사람들이 해결책을 찾았습니다. 여기에는 여러 가지가 나열되어 있습니다.
them and their improved cost.
그들과 그들의 향상된 비용.
First is the smart transformer proposed by Childed L in April of 2019 achieved all of
첫 번째는 2019년 4월 Childed L이 제안한 스마트 트랜스포머로
n times pth root of n times space cost, where p is a hyperparameter independent of n, in
n 곱하기 공간 비용의 n 곱하기 p제곱근, 여기서 p는 n과 독립된 하이퍼파라미터입니다.
their work they gave examples when pth could too, but they claimed that higher dimensions
그들의 작업은 pth도 가능하다는 예를 제시했지만 더 높은 차원이 있다고 주장했습니다.
were also feasible.
가능하기도 했습니다.
Next we have the lean former proposed by Wang Edel in June 2020 and now raised the tension
다음으로 2020년 6월 Wang Edel이 제안한 린 전자가 있으며 이제 긴장감을 높였습니다.
by Kassarou Polos Edel in August 2020, long former by Delta G in December of 2020, random
2020년 8월 Kassarou Polos Edel 작성, 2020년 12월 Delta G에서 오래전 제작, 무작위
feature tension RFA by Peng Edel in March of 2021.
2021년 3월 Peng Edel의 장편 RFA입니다.
See all those four solutions achieved linear time and space cost in various ways and some
네 가지 솔루션 모두 다양한 방식으로 선형적인 시간 및 공간 비용을 달성했으며 일부는
even have constant space cost which we will cover later.
나중에 다루게 될 일정한 공간 비용도 있습니다.
So let's talk about the one by one, first the smart transformers, the motivation behind
그럼 먼저 스마트 트랜스포머에 대해 하나씩 이야기해보겠습니다.
the smart transformer can be explained by the following image, these are learned attention
스마트 변압기는 다음 이미지로 설명할 수 있습니다. 이는 학습된 주의 사항입니다.
patterns from a 1228 layer network on the C4-10 reset train with full attention, divide
완전한 주의를 기울여 C4-10 재설정 열차의 1228 레이어 네트워크에서 패턴을 나누고,
areas such as those ones highlights the attention base for head while generating given pixel
그러한 영역은 주어진 픽셀을 생성하는 동안 머리의 주의 기반을 강조합니다.
while black indicates masked pixels and an ultra-regressive task such as those areas.
검은색은 마스크된 픽셀과 해당 영역과 같은 극도로 회귀적인 작업을 나타냅니다.
It's interesting to note here that the layers are able to learn a variety of specialized
여기서 레이어가 다양한 전문 기술을 학습할 수 있다는 점이 흥미롭습니다.
sparse patterns, so for example in image set A which are from the initial layers we noticed
희소 패턴, 예를 들어 우리가 발견한 초기 레이어의 이미지 세트 A에서
that black areas surrounded the target pixel for example this one and which resembles
예를 들어 이 픽셀은 대상 픽셀을 둘러싸고 있는 검은색 영역입니다.
convolution and in image set B which is from layer 1920 we notice a row and column attention
컨볼루션과 레이어 1920의 이미지 세트 B에서 행과 열에 주의가 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
such as these ones. In further layers such as C we notice a data dependent access patterns
이런 것들. C와 같은 추가 계층에서는 데이터 종속 액세스 패턴을 확인할 수 있습니다.
and so for example the white areas here surround the bird
예를 들어 여기의 흰색 부분이 새를 둘러싸고 있습니다.
and in the final set from layer 64 to 128 whites only appear in a few specific locations as we can see here
레이어 64에서 128까지의 최종 세트에서 흰색은 여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 몇 가지 특정 위치에만 나타납니다.
and sometimes I'm not sure if that one is here so maybe we don't need the full attention maybe
가끔은 그 사람이 여기에 있는지 확실하지 않아서 완전히 주의를 기울일 필요는 없을 수도 있습니다.
sparse attention is enough. Here we explain the motivation in a more mathematical way
주의를 기울이는 것만으로도 충분합니다. 여기서는 보다 수학적 방법으로 동기를 설명합니다.
if you recall the attention function the softmax function and what you're seeing here is just a
어텐션 함수인 소프트맥스 함수를 떠올려 보세요. 여기서 보고 있는 것은 단지
token by token form or the function with the output token only being able to attend the tokens
토큰 형식의 토큰 또는 출력 토큰이 토큰에만 참석할 수 있는 기능
before it. Notice that this is basically the decoder part of the transformer with all the inputs
그 전에. 이는 기본적으로 모든 입력이 포함된 변환기의 디코더 부분입니다.
after the location of target output masked so as you can see here KSI, J can only reach
KSI에서 볼 수 있듯이 대상 출력 위치가 마스크된 후에 J는 도달할 수만 있습니다.
the index specified in SI. So in the full attention mechanism SI here is equal to J
SI에 지정된 인덱스입니다. 따라서 전체 주의 메커니즘에서 SI는 J와 같습니다.
where J is less than or equal to I meaning that the output token for example here can only attend
여기서 J는 I보다 작거나 같습니다. 이는 예를 들어 여기서 출력 토큰이 참석할 수만 있음을 의미합니다.
to all of the previous input vectors. However from what we have seen before this might not be
이전의 모든 입력 벡터에 적용됩니다. 그러나 우리가 이전에 본 바에 따르면 이것이 아닐 수도 있습니다.
necessary so therefore the idea is to separate attention to pay attention has and find efficient
필요하므로 주의를 집중하기 위해 주의를 분리하고 효율적인 방법을 찾는 것이 아이디어입니다.
subset of this SI such that the size of A is proportional to pth root of N.
A의 크기가 N의 p제곱근에 비례하도록 이 SI의 하위 집합입니다.
Here the author proposes two solutions when p is equal to 2. To the left is the full attention
여기에서 저자는 p가 2일 때 두 가지 해법을 제안합니다. 왼쪽에는 전체 주의가 있습니다.
and in the middle they choose the hyperparameter L and in this case 4 and an output token would
중간에 하이퍼파라미터 L을 선택하고 이 경우 4를 선택하며 출력 토큰은
attend to the three tokens before them. For example you have this one attending to the three before
그들 앞에 있는 세 개의 토큰에 주의하세요. 예를 들어 이전에 세 가지에 참석한 사람이 있습니다.
them and also the fourth, the A's before them. The reason for this, the reason for like these
그들과 네 번째, 그들 앞에는 A가 있습니다. 이런 이유, 이런 이유
light blue ones is to maintain full connectivity since this token are not connected to this one
연한 파란색은 이 토큰이 이 토큰에 연결되어 있지 않기 때문에 완전한 연결을 유지하는 것입니다.
or this one. But through the light blue ones since this token, these tokens are connected to
아니면 이것. 하지만 이 토큰 이후 하늘색을 통해 이 토큰들은 다음과 연결됩니다.
the three before it, if this token is connected to it then
그 앞의 세 개, 이 토큰이 연결되어 있으면
we have full connectivity.
우리는 완전한 연결성을 갖고 있습니다.
So this one is named the strided sparse transformer due to its shape.
그래서 이것은 그 모양 때문에 스트라이드 스파스 변환기라고 불립니다.
So to the right we think proposed another solution called the fixed sparse transformer.
그래서 오른쪽에는 고정 희소 변환기(Fixed Sparse Transformer)라는 또 다른 솔루션이 제안되었다고 생각합니다.
In this example the fifth, ninth and thirteenth token
이 예에서는 다섯 번째, 아홉 번째, 열세 번째 토큰입니다.
and also the seventeenth token would attend to the previous three tokens.
또한 17번째 토큰은 이전 3개의 토큰에 참석합니다.
By the fourth, the eighth and the top tokens attending to the previous two
네 번째, 여덟 번째 및 이전 두 개에 참석하는 상위 토큰까지
and also the top. Yeah and two and so on. These are indicated by the dark blue areas as you can see
그리고 꼭대기도. 응, 그리고 두 개 등등. 보시다시피 진한 파란색 영역으로 표시됩니다.
here. So now to maintain full connectivity, the set of four tokens should attend to the last token
여기. 이제 완전한 연결을 유지하려면 4개의 토큰 세트가 마지막 토큰에 참석해야 합니다.
from the previous set. So this one for example should attend to this one and this one should also
이전 세트에서. 예를 들어 이것은 이것에 참석해야 하고 이것도 또한 해야 합니다.
attend to this one to maintain full connectivity indicated by the light blue areas. So these
연한 파란색 영역으로 표시된 완전한 연결을 유지하려면 이 작업에 주의하십시오. 그래서 이것들은
these are just two examples when P equals to two. High dimensions are also possible according to the
이는 P가 2일 때의 두 가지 예일 뿐입니다. 에 따라 높은 치수도 가능합니다.
authors and the calculation here now then is reduced to over and square root of n in this case
저자와 지금 여기의 계산은 이 경우 n의 제곱근 이상으로 축소됩니다.
because the size of these areas are proportional to square root of n.
왜냐하면 이 영역의 크기는 n의 제곱근에 비례하기 때문입니다.
So how about the space capacity? But instead of merely remembering every attention matrices
그렇다면 공간 용량은 어떨까? 하지만 단순히 모든 주의 매트릭스를 기억하는 대신
in here they perform recalculation for the attention at the lower network and instead
여기에서는 하위 네트워크의 주의에 대한 재계산을 수행하고 대신
only seeming the results of the calculation here and here indicated by the gray areas.
여기와 여기의 계산 결과만 회색 영역으로 표시됩니다.
So this is called gradient checkpoint and recomputation.
그래서 이것을 그래디언트 체크포인트 및 재계산이라고 합니다.
Therefore the space capacity is also reduced n times the model which is linear to n.
따라서 공간 용량도 n에 선형인 모델보다 n배 감소합니다.
Which is good when n gets really big.
n이 정말 커지면 좋습니다.
So now let's look at its performance against the state-of-the-art model at the time.
그럼 이제 당시의 최첨단 모델과 비교한 성능을 살펴보겠습니다.
So train and save our 10 new sets and we get the text data set and the means net
따라서 10개의 새로운 세트를 훈련하고 저장하면 텍스트 데이터 세트와 순 평균을 얻습니다.
60 by 4 by 64 new set and a 5 second 12 kHz classical music like classical music.
60 x 4 x 64의 새로운 세트와 클래식 음악과 같은 5초 12kHz 클래식 음악입니다.
So the bits but bits provide here means the number of bits required to generate a byte or a pixel.
따라서 여기서 제공하는 비트는 바이트 또는 픽셀을 생성하는 데 필요한 비트 수를 의미합니다.
The lowest number is the value of the performances.
가장 낮은 숫자는 공연의 가치입니다.
So we can see here the sparse transformers here
여기 희소 변환기를 볼 수 있습니다.
outperformed other models in a single test.
단일 테스트에서 다른 모델보다 성능이 뛰어났습니다.
The speed is also increased as indicated to the right as you can see here.
여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 오른쪽에 표시된 것처럼 속도도 증가합니다.
And at the bottom right you can see that even with long contacts up to 12,160 tokens
그리고 오른쪽 하단에는 최대 12,160개의 토큰까지 긴 연락처가 있는 경우에도 볼 수 있습니다.
the performance is still good.
성능은 여전히 ​​좋다.
Next we talk about Neoformer.
다음으로 Neoformer에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
The idea behind Neoformer is as follows. If you remember the intention function,
네오포머의 아이디어는 다음과 같습니다. 의도 함수를 기억한다면,
the idea behind Neoformer is basically to project the key and value into lower dimensional
Neoformer의 기본 아이디어는 기본적으로 키와 가치를 더 낮은 차원에 투영하는 것입니다.
matrices key time of dimension key times dk with k much smaller than n.
행렬 차원의 키 시간과 k가 n보다 훨씬 작은 dk를 곱합니다.
This way the computation cost will be reduced to all of n times k.
이렇게 하면 계산 비용이 n 곱하기 k 모두로 감소됩니다.
As soon as the dimension of the addition matrix would become n times k the space complexity
덧셈 행렬의 차원이 공간 복잡도의 n배 k가 되자마자
also reduced to n times k times h.
또한 n배 k배 h로 감소됩니다.
Now the question comes whether such predictions exist.
이제 그러한 예측이 존재하는지에 대한 질문이 생깁니다.
Here the author proposed a theorem to show that they do.
여기에서 저자는 그들이 그렇다는 것을 보여주기 위해 정리를 제안했습니다.
The theorem basically showed that for a certain value of k such projections E and F exists.
정리는 기본적으로 k의 특정 값에 대해 그러한 투영 E와 F가 존재한다는 것을 보여주었습니다.
At here k is dependent on n but I noted that the rank of qi k are composed
여기서 k는 n에 의존하지만 qi k의 순위는 다음과 같이 구성됩니다.
divided by square root of dk is at most dk since the dimension of qi is equals to the
dk를 제곱근으로 나눈 값은 qi의 차원이 다음과 같기 때문에 최대 dk입니다.
dimension of ki which equals to n times dk.
n 곱하기 dk와 동일한 ki의 차원.
So this theorem combined with that fact gives the following.
따라서 이 정리는 그 사실과 결합되어 다음을 제공합니다.
That k equals to 9 times log of dk divided by epsilon squared minus epsilon cubed
k는 dk의 로그를 엡실론 제곱 - 엡실론 세제곱으로 나눈 9배와 같습니다.
which is independent of n and ei is equal to delta times r fi is equal to
이는 n과 무관하며 ei는 델타 곱하기 r과 같습니다. fi는 다음과 같습니다.
e to the power of negative delta times r where r is n by k matrix with identically
e를 음의 델타 곱하기 r로 거듭제곱합니다. 여기서 r은 n x k 행렬입니다.
independent entries from id entries from normal distribution with a mean of zero
평균이 0인 정규 분포의 id 항목과 독립된 항목
and the variance of one over k and delta which is equal to one over two to the power of n.
k에 대한 1의 분산과 2에 대한 1의 n승과 같은 델타입니다.
This theorem still holds. So the proof of this theorem combines a bunch of inequality lemmas
이 정리는 여전히 유효합니다. 따라서 이 정리의 증명은 여러 부등식 정리를 결합한 것입니다.
and so on and due to the time constraint I will not delve into the proof in too much details but
등등 그리고 시간 제약으로 인해 증명에 대해 너무 자세히 다루지는 않겠습니다.
just know that we can find a concrete k delta ei and fi so that we can transform
우리가 변환할 수 있도록 구체적인 k 델타 ei와 fi를 찾을 수 있다는 것을 알아두세요
this epsilon max function into the left where ki and vi are predicted into lower dimensions.
이 엡실론 최대 함수는 ki와 vi가 더 낮은 차원으로 예측되는 왼쪽에 있습니다.
So now we look at some examples of these theorems that I have performed to evaluate
이제 우리는 제가 평가하기 위해 수행한 정리의 몇 가지 예를 살펴보겠습니다.
support formulas. Here the value tpl means the validation complexity and the lower that is
수식을 지원합니다. 여기서 tpl 값은 검증 복잡성을 의미하며 그보다 낮은 것은
the less uncertain the model is when predicting the better the performance.
더 나은 성능을 예측할 때 모델의 불확실성이 낮아집니다.
So first to compare the performance with the fixed sequence length but varying k so as we can see
먼저, 고정된 시퀀스 길이와 다양한 k로 성능을 비교해 보겠습니다.
here and here I can see that the validation complexity of the lean former merged very close
여기 저기에서 린 전자의 검증 복잡성이 매우 가깝게 병합된 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
to the standard transformer and even not very much the larger k is the better the performance
표준 변압기에 연결하고 k가 클수록 성능이 더 좋아지는 것은 아닙니다.
as we can see very slightly here if we zoom in a little bit we can see that it is a bit better.
여기서 아주 약간 볼 수 있듯이 조금 확대하면 조금 더 좋아진 것을 알 수 있습니다.
Yeah and next to compare the three different ways to visualize enf so first is the otherwise
네, 다음은 enf를 시각화하는 세 가지 다른 방법을 비교해 보겠습니다. 먼저 다른 방법입니다.
where they use the same e and f for each head
각 머리에 동일한 e와 f를 사용하는 경우
but varying between layers and second is the key value wise we still use the same e for both
하지만 레이어와 두 번째 사이에 변화가 있다는 것이 핵심 값입니다. 우리는 여전히 두 가지 모두에 대해 동일한 e를 사용합니다.
key and values for each head varying between layers and third one is layer wise where they use a single
레이어마다 달라지는 각 헤드의 키와 값과 세 번째 헤드는 단일 헤드를 사용하는 레이어 방식입니다.
e for all layers and all heads the performance of these three ways of sharing did not very much
e 모든 레이어와 모든 헤드에 대해 이 세 가지 공유 방법의 성능은 그리 높지 않았습니다.
but layer rise chain was just a little bit more stable as we can see here finally
하지만 레이어 상승 체인은 여기서 볼 수 있듯이 조금 더 안정적이었습니다.
for fixed k and varying n the bigger n is that's lower the complexity decreases but eventually
고정된 k와 변화하는 n의 경우 n이 클수록 복잡성은 감소하지만 결국에는
emerge to similar values.
비슷한 값으로 나옵니다.
Here let's look at some performances compared to other models they used a Robert A based model
Robert A 기반 모델을 사용한 다른 모델과 비교하여 몇 가지 성능을 살펴보겠습니다.
as a base model trained on the same corpus as burnt they're tested on four different benchmarks
번트와 동일한 코퍼스에서 훈련된 기본 모델로서 4가지 다른 벤치마크에서 테스트되었습니다.
benchmark natural language understanding tasks is varying n and for each n varying k and the same
벤치마크 자연어 이해 작업은 n이 다양하고 각 n에 대해 k가 다양하며 동일합니다.
strategy so we can see that the performance here and here
전략을 통해 여기와 여기에서 성과를 확인할 수 있습니다.
are quite well compared to the baseline and except for this one here but overall on average
기준선과 상당히 잘 비교되었으며 여기를 제외하고는 전반적으로 평균입니다.
the infomerate performed much better than the base lines well not much better but yeah
정보는 기본 라인보다 훨씬 더 나은 성능을 발휘했지만 그다지 좋지는 않지만 그렇습니다.
there is there are like slight improvements
약간의 개선이 있는 것 같습니다
and for this one
그리고 이것 때문에
we look at the time and memory efficiency improvements so lie the left to left is the
시간과 메모리 효율성 향상을 살펴보았으므로 왼쪽에서 왼쪽으로
time saved the right is memory saved the baseline here is the basic transformer
절약된 시간 오른쪽은 저장된 메모리입니다. 여기 기준선은 기본 변환기입니다.
and we can see here we can observe a great improvement over the basic transformer both
여기서 볼 수 있듯이 기본 변압기에 비해 크게 개선된 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
in time and space as it increases
시간과 공간이 늘어나면
so in the longer sequence it is the more obvious improvement is and the higher the project dimension
따라서 시퀀스가 ​​길어질수록 개선이 더 뚜렷해지고 프로젝트 차원이 높아집니다.
k is the less obvious improvement is because as the dimension grows it takes a lot more time
k는 덜 분명한 개선입니다. 왜냐하면 차원이 커짐에 따라 더 많은 시간이 걸리기 때문입니다.
since like time dependencies like n times k it's going to be slower as k grow
n 곱하기 k와 같은 시간 의존성과 마찬가지로 k가 성장함에 따라 속도가 느려질 것입니다.
and next we talk about the linearization
다음으로 선형화에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
by kathropoulos flows in august 2020
작성자: kathropoulos flow, 2020년 8월
here we could recall the definition of the softmax function
여기서 우리는 소프트맥스 함수의 정의를 떠올릴 수 있습니다
and given the sequence x is equal to x1 all the way to xn the i's position of the softmax of x
그리고 주어진 시퀀스에서 x는 x의 소프트맥스의 i 위치인 xn까지 x1과 같습니다.
is equal to e to the power of xi divided by the sum of the exponents of all xi
e는 xi의 거듭제곱을 모든 xi의 지수의 합으로 나눈 값과 같습니다.
so if i let i denote i's row of the matrix y denote the output of the attention mechanism
그래서 내가 행렬의 i 행을 나타내도록 하면 y는 주의 메커니즘의 출력을 나타냅니다.
then i's row of y can be calculated by the following
i의 y 행은 다음과 같이 계산할 수 있습니다.
y equals the softmax of qi times k divided by square root of dk times v
y는 qi 곱하기 k의 소프트맥스를 dk 곱하기 v의 제곱근으로 나눈 것과 같습니다.
talking in the softmax function gives the next part
Softmax 함수로 말하면 다음 부분이 나옵니다
and finally we guess that the top part is can be seen as follows if qi is a vector like this
그리고 마지막으로 qi가 이와 같은 벡터라면 상단 부분은 다음과 같이 볼 수 있다고 추측합니다.
and k oh sorry this should be a transpose here and k is like this
그리고 k 아 죄송합니다. 이것은 여기서 전치여야 하고 k는 이렇습니다
then we have the first row of the
그러면 우리는
this one's q1 this one's q2 the first row of the
이것은 q1입니다. 이것은 q2입니다. 첫 번째 행
the attention matrix would be q1.k1 and q1.k2 and this one times by v
주의 매트릭스는 q1.k1 및 q1.k2가 되며 이는 v에 의해 한 번 수행됩니다.
this is v1 this is v2 would give v1
이것은 v1입니다. 이것은 v2입니다. 그러면 v1이 됩니다.
times
타임스
first
첫 번째
would be v1 times q1.k1 plus v2 times q1.k2
v1 곱하기 q1.k1 더하기 v2 곱하기 q1.k2가 됩니다.
for the whole row all right so this is where we come from
전체 행에 대해 좋습니다. 그래서 이것이 우리가 온 곳입니다
where the sum of q and k is equal to the exponents of q times k divided by square root of dk
여기서 q와 k의 합은 q의 지수 곱하기 k를 dk의 제곱근으로 나눈 값과 같습니다.
here the only constraint by the definition of an attention function is that their
여기서 주의 함수 정의에 따른 유일한 제약은
formation the same function is has to be non-negative so here we do not need to specify the kernel
동일한 함수는 음수가 아니어야 하므로 여기서는 커널을 지정할 필요가 없습니다.
so we only need to specify the feature mark or the feature representation
따라서 특징 표시나 특징 표현만 지정하면 됩니다.
so a feature representation phi of a kernel k is a function such that k of x and y equals
따라서 커널 k의 특징 표현 phi는 x와 y의 k가 다음과 같도록 하는 함수입니다.
is equal to phi of x times phi of y
는 x의 파이 곱하기 y의 파이와 같습니다
so plugging that into the previous equation we have gives the following
이를 이전 방정식에 연결하면 다음이 제공됩니다.
you can take out phi of qi transposed here because the sum does not affect i
합계가 i에 영향을 주지 않기 때문에 여기에서 전치된 qi의 phi를 꺼낼 수 있습니다.
and notice that these sums can be computed once these sums can be treated computed once for every
이 합계는 매회마다 한 번씩 계산되도록 처리할 수 있으면 계산할 수 있습니다.
i and reused now like for for once and you've reused for every i the order should be reversed
나는 지금 한 번만 재사용했고 당신은 매 i마다 재사용했습니다. 순서를 바꿔야 합니다.
yeah the cost for computing the sums depend on n linearly and computing this
네, 합계를 계산하는 비용은 선형적으로 n에 따라 달라지며 이를 계산합니다.
cost o of n since the top sum produce a constant and the bottom sum at the bottom is a dot project
상단 합계는 상수를 생성하고 하단의 하단 합계는 도트 프로젝트이므로 n의 비용 o
and y sub i has d mod rows in total so in the end the modest computational cost is linear to n
그리고 y sub i에는 총 d개의 mod 행이 있으므로 결국 적당한 계산 비용은 n에 선형입니다.
and the the space cost would also be reduced linear to n since we do not need to save the
공간 비용도 n에 선형적으로 감소합니다. 왜냐하면 우리가 공간을 절약할 필요가 없기 때문입니다.
floatation restriction anymore each of these requires our friend to save
부동 제한은 더 이상 친구가 저장해야 합니다.
and the choice of phi x was the in this paper was the exponential linear unit activation function
그리고 이 논문에서 phi x의 선택은 지수 선형 단위 활성화 함수였습니다.
plus one to avoid setting the gradient to zero and xx negative
그래디언트를 0 및 xx 음수로 설정하지 않으려면 1을 더하세요.
so let's come when it's come to causal masking which is a technique used in autoregressive feature
자동 회귀 특성에 사용되는 기술인 인과 마스킹에 대해 알아보겠습니다.
generation mentioned before basically mask the tokens after the target token making only the
앞서 언급한 세대는 기본적으로 대상 토큰 이후의 토큰을 마스크하여
tokens before it visible to that token in this case our equation becomes the following
해당 토큰에 표시되기 전의 토큰 이 경우 방정식은 다음과 같습니다.
we simply replace n by i
우리는 단순히 n을 i로 대체합니다.
and replace the top sum by s i and the bottom sum by z i so notice that s i can be computed from
상위 합을 si로, 하위 합을 zi로 대체하여 si를 다음과 같이 계산할 수 있습니다.
s i minus one and by adding phi k i phi of k i times v i transpose and that i can become the
si 빼기 1에 ki 곱하기 vi 전치의 phi ki phi를 더하면 나는 다음이 될 수 있습니다.
computed from z i minus one by adding phi of k i since the computation of the sums are linear to n
합의 계산이 n에 선형이기 때문에 ki의 phi를 추가하여 zi에서 1을 뺀 값으로 계산됩니다.
and adding those are constant to n we still have a linear time complexity
그리고 그것들을 n에 상수로 더하면 여전히 선형 시간 복잡도를 갖게 됩니다.
but how about the space complexity
하지만 공간 복잡도는 어떻습니까?
here during the back propagation the gradients with respect to q k and v
여기서 역전파 동안 qk와 v에 대한 기울기는 다음과 같습니다.
needs to be computed from the floatation matrix giving a space complexity of o of s square in the
는 제곱의 o의 공간 복잡도를 제공하는 부동 행렬로부터 계산되어야 합니다.
standard transformer but here it also derives the gradients so that the time cost is linear
표준 변압기이지만 여기서는 시간 비용이 선형이 되도록 기울기도 도출합니다.
to the space cost and the space cost is constant
공간 비용에 대한 공간 비용은 일정합니다.
given the numerator from the previous equation and the gradient of the loss function
이전 방정식의 분자와 손실 함수의 기울기가 주어지면
nebulous of y bar of l the authors were able to derive the gradients with respect to phi of
모호한 y bar of l 저자는 의 phi에 대한 기울기를 도출할 수 있었습니다.
q phi phi q of k and v as follows
q phi phi q k와 v는 다음과 같다
we can see that these gradients all require linear to n time
우리는 이러한 그래디언트가 모두 n 시간의 선형을 필요로 한다는 것을 알 수 있습니다
as shown here here and here these calculations
여기 여기와 여기 표시된 것처럼 이러한 계산은
are only like linear to n just because the sum here are there and that many
여기에 합이 거기 있고 그만큼 많기 때문에 n에 선형인 것과 같습니다.
operations these operations are not dependent on n even
이러한 작업은 n에 종속되지 않습니다.
and solving them require constant time because the final values does not depend on n
최종 값은 n에 의존하지 않기 때문에 이를 해결하려면 일정한 시간이 필요합니다.
and a total time and completion cost does all linear overall if combined with
총 시간과 완료 비용은 다음과 결합되면 전반적으로 모두 선형이 됩니다.
previous steps we will omit the discussion regarding the derivation of the gradients because
이전 단계에서는 그라디언트 도출에 관한 논의를 생략하겠습니다.
time and space are limited but if you're interested you can go to the paper and have a read
시간과 공간은 제한되어 있지만 관심이 있으시면 신문에 가서 읽어보실 수 있습니다.
so
그래서
let's move on from what if you have gathered above they formalize the transformers as an
위에 모인 경우 변압기를 다음과 같이 공식화합니다.
recurrent neural network this and i quote is a first step towards better understanding
순환 신경망과 내가 인용하는 것은 더 나은 이해를 향한 첫 번째 단계입니다.
the relationship between transformers and popular recurrent networks and the process
변환기와 대중적인 순환 네트워크 및 프로세스 간의 관계
is used for storing and retrieving information the authors do not specify like why rnn means
rnn이 의미하는 이유와 같이 작성자가 지정하지 않은 정보를 저장하고 검색하는 데 사용됩니다.
linear time space complexity their goal for formulating transformers in this way of another
선형 시공간 복잡도 다른 방식으로 변환기를 공식화하려는 목표
n is just to emphasize the idea that transformers and rnn can be closely related to each other
n은 변환기와 rnn이 서로 밀접하게 관련될 수 있다는 아이디어를 강조하기 위한 것입니다.
so here s of s and z are hidden states x i are easy i's output and y i is the i theme
여기 s와 z는 숨겨진 상태입니다. xi는 쉬운 i의 출력이고 yi는 i 테마입니다.
okay sorry s i is the output and y i is i's output
알았어 미안해 si는 출력이고 yi는 i의 출력이다
now let's look at some experimental results we just quickly run through them and
이제 몇 가지 실험 결과를 살펴보겠습니다. 빠르게 살펴보고
the black line represents all those models and the blue lines are the from the reformer model
검은색 선은 해당 모델을 모두 나타내고 파란색 선은 리포머 모델의 선입니다.
which was another efficient transformer model and the red line here is then a transform
이는 또 다른 효율적인 변압기 모델이었으며 여기 빨간색 선은 변형입니다.
and we can see that the linear attention model performs the rest in both
선형 주의 모델이 두 가지 모두에서 나머지 작업을 수행하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
time and space requirements as the sequences grows
시퀀스가 증가함에 따라 시간 및 공간 요구 사항
next we will look at the convergence of cross entropy loss
다음으로 교차 엔트로피 손실의 수렴을 살펴보겠습니다.
we can see that in the step growth the linear addition model loss
단계적 성장에서 선형 추가 모델 손실이 발생하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
converged to that of a standard transformer while the reformer did not quite reach there
개질기는 표준 변압기에 도달하지 못한 반면 표준 변압기의 변압기에 수렴되었습니다.
so comparing image generation we can see that the linear attention model significantly
따라서 이미지 생성을 비교하면 선형 주의 모델이 크게 향상되었음을 알 수 있습니다.
affirms the other models in terms of speed as seen here although the performance is not the best
성능이 최고는 아니지만 여기에 표시된 속도 측면에서 다른 모델을 확인합니다.
the base per dimension is not the lowest they're still closed to the baseline
차원당 기준이 가장 낮지 않으며 여전히 기준선에 가깝습니다.
and here are just some illustrations of the image generation loss
다음은 이미지 생성 손실에 대한 몇 가지 예시입니다.
and we pause to observe some of them but i will not delve into too much details
그리고 우리는 그 중 일부를 관찰하기 위해 잠시 멈추었지만 너무 많은 세부 사항을 탐구하지는 않을 것입니다.
and finally on speech recognition tasks the linear transformer
마지막으로 음성 인식 작업에서는 선형 변환기를 사용합니다.
model still outperforms the rest in terms of time spent per epoch
모델은 시대당 소요 시간 측면에서 여전히 나머지 모델보다 성능이 뛰어납니다.
it also has lower error rate than two of the baseline models although not outperforming the
또한 두 가지 기본 모델보다 오류율이 낮지만 성능이 우수하지는 않습니다.
standard transformer there is a self max function
표준 변압기에는 자체 최대 기능이 있습니다.
next we will talk about law former by belt g in december 2020
다음으로 2020년 12월 벨트 g의 법률 전직에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
the idea here is quite similar to that of the sparse transformer so we will not
여기서의 아이디어는 희소 변환기의 아이디어와 매우 유사하므로 다루지 않겠습니다.
delve too deep into it so basically they define a fixed window size independent of n
너무 깊이 파고들어 기본적으로 n과 관계없이 고정된 창 크기를 정의합니다.
instead of dependent to n so that the total computational cost and space cost will be linear to
총 계산 비용과 공간 비용이 선형이 되도록 n에 의존하는 대신
n here we show their approaches and they propose three forms of sliding window attention
n 여기에서는 그들의 접근 방식을 보여 주며 그들은 슬라이딩 윈도우 주의의 세 가지 형태를 제안합니다.
first one simply called the sliding window attention and they are given like they provide
첫 번째는 단순히 슬라이딩 윈도우 어텐션(Sliding Window Attention)을 호출하고 제공하는 것처럼 제공됩니다.
at the hyper parameter of like a fixed window size w and each token would attend to one half
고정된 창 크기 w와 같은 하이퍼 매개변수에서 각 토큰은 절반에 참석합니다.
of w token on each side like the one here the second one is called the dilated sliding window
여기에서와 같이 양쪽에 w 토큰이 있습니다. 두 번째 토큰은 확장된 슬라이딩 창이라고 합니다.
which is sliding window with gaps of size dilation d as seen here and the global attention on the
이는 여기에서 볼 수 있듯이 크기 확장 d의 간격이 있는 슬라이딩 창이며,
other hand specify certain tokens that both attend to all other tokens and receive attention from
반면에 다른 모든 토큰에 참여하고 관심을 받는 특정 토큰을 지정합니다.
all other tokens for example for classification global attention is used for the cls token
예를 들어 글로벌 관심 분류를 위한 다른 모든 토큰은 cls 토큰에 사용됩니다.
while specifying the global attention is tax specific it is an easy way to add
글로벌 관심을 지정하는 것은 세금에 따라 다르지만 추가하는 쉬운 방법입니다.
inductive bias to the model's attention and it is much simpler than existing task specific
모델의 주의에 대한 귀납적 편향이 있으며 기존 작업별 것보다 훨씬 간단합니다.
approaches that use complex architecture to combine information across similar
복잡한 아키텍처를 사용하여 유사한 정보를 결합하는 접근 방식
like smaller input chunks so what it did is to combine the diet the sliding window and global
더 작은 입력 덩어리와 마찬가지로 슬라이딩 창과 전역 다이어트를 결합한 것입니다.
attention for example in those tokens here and here and the ones here
예를 들어 여기와 여기의 토큰과 여기에 있는 토큰에 주의를 기울이세요.
and since those are independent of n because the global sliding window the
전역 슬라이딩 윈도우가 n에 독립적이기 때문에
sorry for the global plus sliding window approach they use two sets of q k and v
전역 플러스 슬라이딩 윈도우 접근 방식에 대해 죄송합니다. 그들은 qk와 v의 두 세트를 사용합니다.
similar to that of the sparse transformer yes but they are all initialized to be the same
희소 변환기와 유사하지만 모두 동일하게 초기화됩니다.
and there's a number of such global tokens as smaller relative to n so the total computational
n에 비해 작은 글로벌 토큰이 많이 있으므로 전체 계산은
cost is still independent to n and therefore is linear to n
비용은 여전히 ​​n에 독립적이므로 n에 선형입니다.
now let's come to some experiments here dbc is dpc is equal to the equivalent concept to
이제 여기서 몇 가지 실험을 해보겠습니다. dbc는 dpc가 다음과 같은 개념입니다.
base per pixel in terms of text text base task you can see that long former has the best
텍스트 기반 작업 측면에서 픽셀당 기본이 길다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
small model of vpc on tx8 and nvk data set and close to best dpc for large models on
tx8 및 nvk 데이터 세트의 작은 vpc 모델 및 대형 모델의 경우 최고의 dpc에 가깝습니다.
nvk so yes we can see here the right it shows comparison within the model for different
nvk이므로 예, 여기에서 오른쪽을 볼 수 있습니다. 이는 모델 내에서 다른 항목에 대한 비교를 보여줍니다.
mode of sliding windows and dilation
슬라이딩 윈도우 및 팽창 모드
and to the bottom right it tests several of our configurations
오른쪽 하단에서는 여러 가지 구성을 테스트합니다.
here we show some other accuracy results for q and a
여기에서는 q와 a에 대한 다른 정확도 결과를 보여줍니다.
for referencing classification compared to barbata and current leaderboard
바르바타 및 현재 순위표와 비교한 분류 참조용
as of current as of may of 2020
2020년 5월 현재 기준
so you'll see here an offmer based how to perform the robot based and the score is pretty good
여기에서 로봇을 기반으로 수행하는 방법을 기반으로 한 오프머를 볼 수 있으며 점수는 꽤 좋습니다.
and the final final uh just more results you may pause and read them if you want to but
그리고 마지막 결승전 어 그냥 더 많은 결과를 원한다면 일시 중지하고 읽어도 되지만
i think i should move on due to the limited time so lastly we come to running feature tension of
시간이 부족해서 계속 진행해야 할 것 같아서 마지막으로 장편 텐션을 실행하게 되었습니다.
a proposed to proposed by punk l in march of 2021 and the idea here is inspired by linearized
2021년 3월에 punk l이 제안한 제안이며 여기의 아이디어는 선형화에서 영감을 받았습니다.
attention first we introduce the preliminary theorem used if we let wi be independently
먼저 wi를 독립적으로 두는 경우 사용되는 예비 정리를 소개합니다.
sampled vectors from a normal distribution with zero mean and sigma squared times the identity
평균이 0이고 시그마 제곱에 항등을 곱한 정규 분포에서 샘플링된 벡터
matrix outside the variance in this like in other words like let each entry in wi be sampled from
즉, wi의 각 항목을 다음에서 샘플링하도록 하는 것과 같습니다.
the normal distribution we and let
정규분포 우리와 하자
phi i at flip five be a non-linear transformation from r small r small d to r two times big d
phi i는 5번 반전에서 r 작은 r 작은 d에서 r 2배 큰 d로의 비선형 변환입니다.
where phi of vector x is equal to square root of one over big d times the transpose of sign of
여기서 벡터 x의 파이는 부호의 전치에 큰 d를 곱한 1의 제곱근과 같습니다.
w one dot x all the way to sign of w d dot x and cosine of w one dot x all the way to cosine of w
w 하나의 점 x wd의 부호까지 계속 도트 x 그리고 w의 코사인 하나의 점 x w의 코사인까지
d x transpose then we take as expected values of phi i time the phi x times y is
dx 전치 그런 다음 우리는 phi i 시간 phi x 곱하기 y의 예상 값을 취합니다.
i excuse me given wi is the exponent of the length of x minus y squared divided by two
실례합니다. wi는 x - y 제곱의 길이를 2로 나눈 지수입니다.
times sigma squared negated and here we notice that big d is a hyper parameter
곱하기 시그마 제곱이 부정되고 여기서 우리는 큰 d가 하이퍼 매개변수임을 알 수 있습니다.
independent of sequence length so how does this theorem help us well now we can perform the following
시퀀스 길이와 무관하므로 이 정리가 어떻게 우리에게 도움이 됩니까? 이제 다음을 수행할 수 있습니다.
operation the exponents of q are transpose times k i divided by square root of dk equals to this
연산 q의 지수는 전치 곱하기 ki를 dk의 제곱근으로 나눈 값입니다.
formula here we simply just square the inside and separate them
공식은 그냥 내부를 제곱해서 분리하면 됩니다
and here we notice the second components is second the second components can be replaced
여기서 두 번째 구성 요소는 두 번째 구성 요소를 교체할 수 있다는 것을 알 수 있습니다.
like now we can use the theorem before to replace it with its kind of representation
지금처럼 우리는 이전의 정리를 사용하여 그 종류의 표현으로 대체할 수 있습니다.
to obtain this final form now we can see why this work is inspired by linearization
이 최종 형태를 얻으려면 이제 이 작업이 선형화에서 영감을 받은 이유를 알 수 있습니다.
we call that the attention function from the linear attention
우리는 이것을 선형 주의로부터 주의 함수라고 부릅니다.
so right here we just replace the same function with what we have here and define what
그래서 바로 여기에서 동일한 함수를 여기에 있는 함수로 바꾸고 무엇을 정의하면 됩니다.
we define what we obtain as r f a of g i k v
우리는 gikv의 rfa로 얻은 것을 정의합니다.
so all times here this all times here denote the out the output which produced matrix whose
그래서 여기의 모든 시간은 여기의 모든 시간이 다음과 같은 행렬을 생성한 출력을 나타냅니다.
entries are all products of n element in the first vector with n element in the second vector
항목은 모두 첫 번째 벡터의 n 요소와 두 번째 벡터의 n 요소의 곱입니다.
corresponding so for example if i have two vectors they produce the cross product produce this matrix
예를 들어 두 개의 벡터가 있는 경우 교차곱이 생성되어 이 행렬이 생성됩니다.
and so on and so forth
등등 등등
and here we will discuss the time and space complexity of r f a here we just use a different
여기서는 rfa의 시간 및 공간 복잡성에 대해 논의하겠습니다. 여기서는 다른 방법을 사용합니다.
letter but it's basically the same idea in this case which is called the gaussian
편지이지만 가우스라고 불리는 이 경우에는 기본적으로 동일한 아이디어입니다.
chrono five qt or five qi takes time 2d 2 times dk 2 times c times dk and space of 2d
크로노 5 qt 또는 5 qi에는 시간 2d 2 곱하기 dk 2 곱하기 c 곱하기 dk 및 2d의 공간이 필요합니다.
and this product cross product here takes time 2 times n times d times dk and space of 2 times d
그리고 이 곱의 교차곱은 시간 2 곱하기 n 곱하기 d 곱하기 dk 와 2 곱하기 d 의 공간이 필요합니다.
times dk and
타임즈 dk 그리고
summation here alone takes time of all of 2n times dk d times dk and space of all of 2d
여기서만 합산하는 데는 2n 곱하기 dk d 곱하기 dk의 시간과 2d의 공간이 모두 필요합니다.
and the opposition with five qt the dot products here and here takes time 2d k therefore the time
여기와 여기에서 5개의 qt 내적을 갖는 반대는 시간이 걸립니다. 2d k 따라서 시간은
is the full time is linear to n and the memory total memory is 4d plus 2d
풀타임은 n에 선형이고 메모리 총 메모리는 4d + 2d입니다.
dk which is constant but it highly depends on d
dk는 일정하지만 d에 크게 의존합니다.
and the virtual experiment shows that when d is greater than 2 times little d
가상 실험에서는 d가 작은 d의 2배보다 클 때
depending on this is marginal so like the linearized attention this again gives us an
이것에 의존하는 것은 미미하므로 선형화된 주의와 마찬가지로 이것은 다시 우리에게
argument in case of causal attention now i need to remind everyone here that this does not explain
인과관계에 대한 관심이 있는 경우 논쟁에 대해 지금 여기 있는 모든 사람에게 이것이 설명되지 않는다는 점을 상기시켜야 합니다.
why time as speaks complexity is linear and this is this simply just strengthen the relationship
복잡성이 말하는 시간이 선형인 이유는 이것이 단순히 관계를 강화하는 것입니다.
between a transformer and an rnn so due to this rnn like property rfa can be made stateful
변환기와 rnn 사이에 있으므로 이 rnn으로 인해 rfa와 같은 속성을 상태 저장으로 만들 수 있습니다.
so that is we can pass last in the states
그러면 우리는 주에서 마지막으로 통과할 수 있습니다
st and zt to the next mini batch during both training and devaluation we will see later that
훈련과 평가절하 동안 st와 zt를 다음 미니 배치로 이동합니다. 나중에 살펴보겠습니다.
this improves the problems quite a bit so another benefits that rnn like form gives us is the ability
이는 문제를 상당히 개선하므로 형식과 같은 rnn이 우리에게 제공하는 또 다른 이점은 다음과 같습니다.
to learn previously bias with our gt mechanism here wg and bg are learning parameters and gt is
gt 메커니즘을 사용하여 이전에 편향을 학습하려면 여기서 wg와 bg는 학습 매개변수이고 gt는
between 0 and 1 the hidden states are multiplied by gt which is the learned scatter so that the
0과 1 사이에서 숨겨진 상태에 학습된 분산인 gt를 곱하여
history is exponentially decayed if you were in the most recent context
당신이 가장 최근의 상황에 있었다면 역사는 기하급수적으로 쇠퇴합니다
so those are besides the gaussian kernel also proposed an arc cosine kernel
그래서 그것들은 가우스 커널 외에 아크 코사인 커널도 제안했습니다.
they chose from a family of chipped variant kernel to rectify linear unity activation function
그들은 선형 통합 활성화 함수를 수정하기 위해 부서진 변형 커널 제품군 중에서 선택했습니다.
here the redo function is simply the max of 0 and x this achieves no results and is
여기서 다시 실행 기능은 단순히 0과 x의 최대값입니다. 이는 결과를 얻지 못하며
supplements to alternative to self max again besides the gaussian kernel
가우스 커널 외에 self max에 대한 대안 보완
so here let's look at some experimentation results
그럼 몇 가지 실험 결과를 살펴보겠습니다.
and the baseline used here is the linearized attention
여기에 사용된 기준선은 선형화된 주의입니다.
here compared with the variances proposed in this one we can see that in terms of
여기에서 제안된 분산과 비교하면 다음과 같은 점을 알 수 있습니다.
propensity the gt variant performs much better than the baseline and on gt ones as we can see here
성향은 여기서 볼 수 있듯이 gt 변형이 기준선과 gt 변형보다 훨씬 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다.
and yeah the city of awareness performs even better
네, 인식의 도시는 훨씬 더 나은 성능을 발휘합니다
and when it comes to machine translation where the baseline is the standard transformer we're
기준선이 표준 변환기인 기계 번역의 경우 우리는
going to see that the speed of rfa is nearly as smooth as the linearized attention
rfa의 속도가 선형화된 주의만큼 매끄럽다는 것을 알게 될 것입니다.
shown here while the performance is near the baseline and better than linear
성능이 기준선에 가깝고 선형보다 나은 동안 여기에 표시됩니다.
attention as shown for example here
예를 들어 여기에 표시된 대로 주의를 기울이세요.
and here is just a comparison with other models on different text data sets
다음은 다양한 텍스트 데이터 세트에 대한 다른 모델과의 비교입니다.
and we can see that it has like an outstanding accuracy among the test models
테스트 모델 중 정확도가 매우 뛰어난 것을 확인할 수 있습니다.
and it did not but it did not lead in terms of speed and memory consumption
그렇지는 않았지만 속도와 메모리 소비 측면에서 앞서지 않았습니다.
but still it is reached quite up there for example here
하지만 여전히 거기에 도달했습니다. 예를 들어 여기
and finally we look at the comparison of to the softmax function
마지막으로 소프트맥스 함수와의 비교를 살펴보겠습니다.
of the two rfa variances in terms of decoding speed and memory consumption
디코딩 속도와 메모리 소비 측면에서 두 가지 rfa 차이 중
notice that the x scale is log 2 based
x 스케일은 로그 2 기반이라는 점에 유의하세요.
as questions growth the speed of softmax clearly shows a quadratic decay
질문 성장으로 소프트맥스의 속도는 분명히 2차 붕괴를 보여줍니다.
while the speed of rfa in both variances did not vary much it even dropped a little bit
두 가지 분산 모두에서 rfa의 속도는 크게 다르지 않았지만 약간 떨어졌습니다.
oh sorry it went up a little bit but then dropped a little bit again
아 미안 조금 올랐다가 다시 조금 떨어졌어
and in terms of memory consumption softmax grows correctly while rfa remains almost constant
메모리 소비 측면에서 Softmax는 올바르게 증가하지만 rfa는 거의 일정하게 유지됩니다.
so that's all the solutions proposed I will use today and as a final note I will present
이것이 제가 오늘 사용할 제안된 솔루션의 전부이고 마지막으로 제시할 내용은 다음과 같습니다.
a github page comparing all the efficient transformers
모든 효율적인 변환기를 비교하는 github 페이지
shot to Professor Wen Hu Chen for this page
이 페이지의 Wen Hu Chen 교수에게 사진을 찍었습니다.
and this website lists all the efficient transformers as of the 8th of November 2020
이 웹사이트에는 2020년 11월 8일 현재 모든 효율적인 변압기 목록이 나와 있습니다.
and the performance comparisons as shown in this chart
이 차트에 표시된 성능 비교
you can go to this link for more information about it
이 링크로 이동하면 이에 대한 자세한 내용을 확인할 수 있습니다.
and that's it thank you for your time
그게 다야 시간 내주셔서 감사합니다